Full Stack Developer

Autodidact Full stack developer with 2+ years of experience working remotely. Dedicated to developing with best practices and improving the UX/UI, managing mainly the MERN stack and everything related to javascript. Enthusiast about the philosophy of clean coder, extreme ownership and DRY (Don't repeat yourself). Always motivated to learn new technologies and grow as a professional.

EXPERIENCE

Vinco Orbis, remote. Full stack developer — 2019-2021

Company dedicated to web development, apps and project management. Founding member of the National Chamber of the Software Industry, certified partner for Docker consulting and implementation and certified to offer Google services for companies.

- Planned, designed, developed and tested 2+ projects from zero, using agile methodologies for managing projects and time, reducing approximately 50% to calculate reports by hand and some financial operations. Clients- BBVA, Vinco Orbis.
- Maintained back office and Application for Auction house, Implemented functionality to add and display cashiers checks. Client- Private.

Tech stack: Javascript, React JS, Next JS, Material UI, CSS, SWR, Ruby On Rails, Postgresql, Docker, CircleCl, Redux, PHP, CAKEPHP, redis, MongoDB, MYSQL, Sequelize

Axented, remote. Front end developer — 2021-Present

Company dedicated to web development, apps and UX/UI design.

• Developed and tested projects from zero, using agile methodologies to connect talents (programmers) with companies. Client- Internal.

Tech stack: Typescript, Vue JS, Tailwind.

SKILLS

Programming languages: Javascript (3+ YOE), PHP (2+ YOE)

Frameworks, libraries and tools:

• Proficient: Node JS, Next JS, React JS, Redux, Vue JS, Tailwind, Express JS, GIT, JSX, Styled components, API REST, Docker, CSS, Unit tests.

• Familiar: React native, Ruby on Rails, GO, Typescript, Circle-Cl, UX-Ul, Context, Zustand, Cake PHP.

Database: MYSQL, Mongo, Postgresql.

Project Management: SCRUM (Agile methodology).

LANGUAGES

English, intermediate. Spanish, native.

EDUCATION

Universidad Politécnica de Pachuca – Zempoala, Hidalgo. *Bachelor of Science, Software Engineering,* 2016 - 2019.